loaded.co.uk 2019-09-21

# Privacy Policy – Loaded

##  conditions of use

This page contains both the Privacy and Cookies policies of “Loaded”.

“Loaded” is a trading style and Registered Trade Mark owned by Downdaniel Investment Holdings Limited and licensed to The Color Company TM Limited. A company registered in England and Wales at 27a Poland Street, London W1F 8QW. Company No. 05266481 Registration No. GB 849 7664 60.

.It is your responsibility to read and understand our Privacy and Cookie policies. You should also read and understand our [Terms](https://loaded.co.uk/terms/).

These Privacy and Cookies policies govern your use of all services provided on any digital and/or printed platforms by “Loaded”. These are henceforth known as the ‘Service’, where “Loaded” may be referred to below as ‘We’, ‘Us’ and/or ‘The Site’.

By visiting the Service you are agreeing and consenting to the practices described in this privacy and cookies policy.  If you do not agree to these policies do not wish to be bound by them, you are not authorised to access or otherwise use the Service.

Our legal status under UK data protection law is that of a data controller and in this capacity we will securely store and process your personal information which you have provided to us. Data controller is a legal term used in the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) to signify the person who controls what to do with any given personal information.

We are committed to safeguarding your privacy online and pledge not to distribute such information indiscriminately. You should be aware this privacy and cookies policy may change, so, although we strive to keep users updated of such changes, you are asked to check back here frequently to monitor such alterations. If you do not agree with all the below policies, please do not use the Service.

The below policies are split into two sections, (a) and (b) which explain the following.

## a. privacy

a.1. introduction to collecting information  
a.2. accessing your personal data  
a.3. how your data is collected  
a.4. how to opt out of receiving promotional material  
a.5. can other websites use the data we collect?  
a.6. how your data will be processed  
a.7. how your data will be shared  
a.8. the use of your data on social media and in social advertising  
a.9. how we use your data  
a.10. contacting us about our privacy policy

## b. cookies

b.1. what are cookies and why are they used?  
b.2. what type of cookies do we use?  
b.3. can third parties use our cookies?  
b.4. can cookies be disabled or deleted?

## a. privacy policy

## a.1. introduction to collecting information

a.1.1. “Loaded” collects Personal Data and Anonymous Data when you visit our sites or when you send us communications.

a.1.2. ‘Personal Data’ means information that allows someone to identify you. This includes your name, address, telephone number and email address. It also includes information about who you are associated with or linked to.

a.1.3. ‘Anonymous Data’ means information that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Data. Anonymous Data does not permit the identification of an individual person or persons. We collect Personal Data and Anonymous Data as described below.

## a.2. accessing your personal data

a.2.1. You are entitled to see the information held about you and may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure it is accurate and kept up to date. If you wish to see the information we hold about you, please contact us in writing at “Loaded”, 27A Poland Street, London W1F 8QW.

a.2.2. We are entitled by law to charge a fee of £10 to meet costs in providing details of the information we hold about you. We are also legally obliged to request you to provide us with identification so we can be certain you are entitled to receive the requested data.

## a.3. how your data is collected

a.3.1. We collect Personal Data from you such as your name, contact details, country of residence, zip code or post code, gender or birth date when you register on our Service or when you choose to use the various services we provide.

a.3.2. We collect other types of Personal Data you provide to us voluntarily. This can include making a purchase, responding to surveys or entering a competition.

a.3.3. If you provide us feedback regarding our Service via email we will collect your name and email address in order to send you a reply.

a.3.4. In order to improve our Service we may ask you to voluntarily complete confidential surveys. We do not ask you to provide us with any personally identifiable data in association with these surveys, although we do associate your responses with Personal Data. If you do not wish to participate in a survey, simply decline to participate when asked.

a.3.5. If you decide to invite a friend or family member to join our Service, we will collect your name and email address as well as your friend or family member’s email address in order to send them email. We will always ask your permission if we want to mention your details when contacting your friend or family member.

## a.4. how to opt out of receiving promotional material

a.4.1. We offer you choices regarding the collection, use and sharing of your Personal Data.  
When you register on one of our sites or respond to one of our communications or offers we will ask you if you want to receive future communications from us. You may indicate consent to receipt of these communications by entering your personal details and choosing what information you would like to receive, or by not ticking the opt-out box provided.

a.4.2. Should you decide to stop receiving further communications from us you will have the opportunity to opt-out by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the email you receive.[  
](mailto:editorial@loaded.co.uk)

a.4.3. You shall receive a weekly newsletter, The Loaded Edit, when you register with the Loaded.co.uk Service. You can unsubscribe from this communication by clicking on the ‘Unsubscribe’ option in the newsletter.

a.4.4. If you wish to contact us by email or post to opt out of any of our services, or to amend your details, please include your full name and address to allow us to process your request.

a.4.5. To amend your log-in details but stay part of the “Loaded” service, please email your details and request to admin@loaded.co.uk.

## a.5. can other websites use the data we collect?

a.5.1. Except as otherwise expressly provided in this Privacy Policy or on this website, only “Loaded” and its affiliate companies collect Personal Data through the services provided solely by “Loaded”. This Privacy Policy applies only to the use and disclosure of Personal Data we collect while you use our Service.

a.5.2. Although we work with third parties, our display of advertisements or links to any other company or site is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such company or site. We have no control over and our Privacy and Cookies policies does not apply to these other companies, their sites or content or to any collection of data after you click on an advertisement or link controlled by a third party.

## a.6. how your data will be processed

a.6.1. Your Personal Data may be processed both in and outside of your own country. When you submit your details and in whichever country you are situated you agree to the data being transferred to the UK and processed under the terms of the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy & Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 which stem from European Directives 95/46/EC and 2002/58/EC respectively. If you are not in agreement, please do not give us your personal details.

a.6.2. We may need to transfer your data outside the UK (and possibly to places outside the European Economic Area) and by using “Loaded”’s Service, or by responding to our communications, you consent to us transferring any such data in this way. However, any company, whether inside or outside the EEA, to whom we transfer data is contractually bound to protect your Personal Data.

a.6.3. “Loaded” and our affiliates are committed to protecting the security of your Personal Data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Data from unauthorised access, use, or disclosure.

a.6.4. We store Personal Data behind a firewall, a barrier designed to prevent outsiders from accessing our servers. We may also require you to enter a password to access or update your account information. In addition, “Loaded” protects your Personal Data from unauthorised physical access by storing your Personal Data in a controlled facility.

a.6.5. Except as provided elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, “Loaded” limits access to Personal Data in electronic databases to those persons (including employees and contractors) in “Loaded”’s organisation who have a business need for such access. Those persons are under contract to keep your data secure.

a.6.6. Even though “Loaded” has taken significant steps to ensure your Personal Data is not intercepted, accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorised persons, you should know”Loaded” cannot eliminate security risks associated with Personal Data.

## a.7. how your data will be shared

a.7.1. We will share your Personal Data with our third party suppliers who need to process your data in order to fulfil your request, such as to charge your credit card (if authorised by you), fill your order, and deliver electronic newsletters and promotional emails. These third parties are required under contract not to use your Personal Data other than to provide the services requested by “Loaded” and to guarantee to our satisfaction they have sufficient processes in place to ensure the security of your data whilst it is in their care.

a.7.2. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Data with our contractors and third party service providers for the purpose of providing services to you. If you send a testimonial or comment to us we may post it on our site or use it in advertising materials such as posters, website adverts and in print media such as newspapers and magazines.

a.7.3. Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Data,”Loaded” may disclose Personal Data if it believes in good faith such disclosure is necessary to (i) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us or (ii) protect or defend the rights or property of “Loaded” or users of our services.

a.7.4. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that firm will possess the Personal Data collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy and the terms under which you submitted your data.

a.7.5. If you provide “Loaded” with your contact details and agree to receive promotional messages we may share your details with our affiliates or third-party businesses that offer goods or services we believe may be of interest to our customers. Many customers appreciate the offerings they receive from such third parties. However, we allow you to opt out at any time of having your Personal Data shared with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties for the purpose of sending you relevant information.

## a.8. the use of your data on social media & in social advertising

a.8.1. We work with trusted third parties including social network sites such as Facebook, Google+, Instagram, Pinterest, Twitter and YouTube. We also work and with application developers who specialise in social media so we can connect to your social networks. All of these companies operate Third Party Sites. We provide access to our Service by third parties and business partners so we can generate interest in our products and services among members of your social networks and to allow you to share product and service interests with contacts in your network.

a.8.2. We cannot control how your data is collected, stored, used or shared by Third Party Sites or to whom it is disclosed. Please be sure to review the privacy policies and privacy settings on your social networking sites to make sure you understand the information they are sharing.

a.8.3. If you do not want a Third Party Site to share information about you, contact that site and determine whether it gives you the opportunity to opt out of sharing such information. “Loaded” is not responsible for how these third parties may use information collected from or about you.

## a.9. how we use your data

a.9.1. “Loaded” uses your Personal Data to provide you with a customised Service. This includes sending you marketing messages if you have given us permission to do so, processing your answers to quizzes and competitions and sending newsletters and promotional material via e-mail to you.

a.9.2. We use Personal Data for customer service messages, to respond to your requests and to notify you about updates to the Service.

a.9.3. We may create Anonymous Data records from Personal Data by excluding information such as your name and address which makes the data personally identifiable to you. We use this Anonymous Data to perform statistical analyses of users’ behaviour so we may enhance the content of our Service and improve site navigation. “Loaded” reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties at its discretion, in aggregate form.

a.9.4. If you elect to receive communications from us we may periodically send you free newsletters and emails that directly promote the use of our sites or the purchase of our products or services. These may contain advertisements for third parties. You will be able to opt out of such communications by writing to us by email or letter or following the ‘unsubscribe’ instructions included in such communications.

## a.10. contacting us about our privacy policy

a.10.1. You are welcome to ask questions regarding our Privacy Policy as set out above. Should you wish to do so, please email [editorial@loaded.co.uk](mailto:editorial@loaded.co.uk), or write to “Loaded”, 27A Poland Street, London W1F 8QW

a.10.2. If you feel “Loaded” has not adhered to our Terms or Privacy and Cookies policies please email [complaints@loaded.co.uk](mailto:complaints@loaded.co.uk) so that we can begin investigating your dispute, or write to us at at the above address.

## b. cookies policy

## b.1. what are cookies and why are they used?

b.1.1. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer or mobile or tablet device when you first visit one of our web pages.

b.1.2. We use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve the site. The cookies we use enable us to recognise your device so you don’t have to give the same information several times during one task.

b.1.3. Cookies recognise when you have given your username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page you visit. They also measure how many people use our websites so we can make it easier to use and ensure there is enough capacity to make the site as responsive as possible.

b.1.4. Certain cookies contain personal information. For example, if you click on a ‘Remember me’ button when you log in a cookie will store your username.

b.1.5. Most cookies will not collect information that personally identifies you. They will collect more general information such as how users arrive at and use our websites, or a user’s general location.

## b.2. what type of cookies do we use?

b.2.1. Cookies used by “Loaded” perform up to four different functions, as follows.  
          b.2.1.1. Strictly Necessary cookies are required for the operation of our Service. They include cookies which enable you to log in to secure areas of our Service.  
          b.2.1.2. Analytical & Performance Cookies These are cookies allowing “Loaded” to recognise and count the number of visitors to the Service. They enable us to see how visitors move around the Service while using it. This information helps us to improve the way the Service works by, for example, ensuring users can easily find what they are looking for.  
          b.2.1.3. Functional Cookies These are used to recognise your device when you return to our Service. They enable us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember choices such as your language or country.  
          b.2.1.4. Tracking Cookies These record your visits to our Service, the pages you view and the links you follow. We use this information to make our Service and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

## b.3. can third parties use our cookies?

b.3.1. Please note third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services such as web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies on our website. For example, advertisers may use a profile they have built on sites you have previously visited to present you with more relevant advertisements during your visit to our website. We have no control over third party cookies.

b.3.2. Cookies used by third parties are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or tracking cookies. Third party cookies cannot be used to identify you personally and can only be used for statistical analysis. For example, they provide you with advertisements more relevant to your interests. If you are based in the European Union and would like to learn more about how advertisers use these types of cookies, or to choose not to receive them, please visit [youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). If you are based in the United States and would like to learn more, please visit [aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)/.

## b.4. can cookies be disabled or deleted?

b.4.1. If you would like to disable third party cookies you can do so by going to the relevant third party website and opting out there. Please note if you opt out of third party advertising cookies, you will still continue to receive advertising when using the website. However, such advertising will no longer be tailored to you.

b.4.2. You can use your browser settings to restrict or block cookies set by “Loaded”. The Help function within your browser should tell you how to activate the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. Alternatively, you may wish to visit [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information about how to restrict or block cookies on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find information on that website about how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.

b.4.3. If you use your browser settings to block all cookies, including essential cookies, you may not be able to access all or parts of our Service.

“Loaded” is a trading style and Registered Trade Mark owned by Downdaniel Investment Holdings Limited and licensed to The Color Company TM Limited. A company registered in England and Wales at 27a Poland Street, London W1F 8QW. Company No. 05266481 Registration No. GB 849 7664 60.
